# **Pranav Raikote**

#### **COMPUTER VISION PRACTITIONER**

Passionate researcher and practitioner in Deep Learning having 2+ years of experience in Computer Vision & allied domains. Seeking an opportunity to exhibit my skills and contribute to the organization with my expertise.

pranavraikote@gmail.com +91-9448210677 pranavraikote.github.io github.com/pranavraikote medium.com/@pranavraikote

#### **EDUCATION**

## B.Tech - Computer Science & Engineering BMS Institute of Technology & Management

- Aug 2016 October 2020
- CGPA 7.62/10.0

#### **Pre-University Education**

KLE S Nijalingappa PU College

- Mar 2014 Mar 2016
- Percentage 70%

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Deep Learning Intern**

DeepVisionTech.AI

- Aug 2020 Oct 2020
- Worked on Generative Adversarial Networks to generate realistic videos as part of dataset synthesis problem statement

#### **Developer Intern**

Simplifi Commerce

- Aug 2019 Oct 2019
- Implemented Proof of Concepts in Python, Image Processing and Deep Learning
- Worked on Full-Stack development in NodeJS as part of a website requirement

#### **Machine Learning Consultant**

#### Infidata Technologies

- Jul 2019 Aug 2019
- Worked as a Technical Consultant for various student led project teams guiding them in developing Machine Learning Solutions

### POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

#### Chairperson IEEE Student Branch, BMSIT&M Nov 2019 - Aug 2020

 Successfully led a team towards greater goals and sustained efforts throughout my tenure bringing a positive impact in our institution and beyond

### **IEEE R10 Students Activities Committee**

Feb 2020 - Present

 Contributed in writing content being a part of the Media and Publicity Sub-Committee

#### **SKILLS**

- Python
- JAVA
- C Programming
- TensorFlow
- Cloud Computing
- Linux

#### **PROJECTS**

### Diagnosis of COVID-19 from Chest X-Rays

Apr 2020 - Present

- Designed and developed a Deep Learning Ensemble Model which can give a diagnostic presence of Viral infection in a Chest X-Ray
- Extensive research on Image pre-processing, Model building and HPO techniques carried out and materialized using TensorFlow

## Diagnosis of Pneumonia from Chest X-Rays Dec 2019 - Apr 2020

- Designed and developed a Deep Learning Model for a quick and state of the art results on diagnosis of Pneumonia in a Chest X-Ray
- Data cleaning,pre-processing per image basis was carried out and SOTA architectures were explored to improve on the current industry results. Stanford Medical Group's ChexPert data was used

#### **Detection of Road Lanes from a Video Stream** Apr 2020 - Apr 2020

- Developed an end-to-end Image processing pipeline for detecting lanes on road given a video input or live stream
- Various Image processing filters and techniques were used to arrive at the lane markers. Potential to be developed as a solution for custom fitting into cars for driving assistance

## Image Caption Generator using LSTM & CNN Mar 2020 - Mar 2020

 Developed a Caption Generator which on given an input will generate multiple-word descriptions. Model was a combination of LSTM and a CNN

## Intrepretation of Sign Language from a Video Jan 2020 - Mar 2020

 Used CNN and Image pre=processing techniques to build a Deep Learning model which on given an input video, will extract frames and output an inference sentence depicting the action

## **Extraction of Useful Information from Images** July 2019 - Sep 2019

 Developed an automation application to extract valuable information given a pdf document. Tesseract OCR and MySQL DB were used for effective extraction and storage of results respectively

### CERTIFICATIONS

#### **Deep Learning Specialization (May 2019)**

• 5 courses

#### AI in Medicine Specialization (May 2019)

• 3 courses

#### **Tensorflow Specialization (Jun 2019)**

• 4 courses